[sweeping orchestral music]
[席卷管弦乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
[animal sounds]
[动物的声音]
Hello, animal control.
你好，动物管理局。
Ew.
呃。
SpongeBob, I appreciate
海绵宝宝，我欣赏
you volunteering here
at the animal shelter,
你在这里做志愿者
在动物收容所，
but could you please stop
letting the worms
但你能停下来吗
让蠕虫
use the phone?
使用电话？
Oh, I told them no more
takeout calls.
哦，我不再告诉他们了
叫外卖。
[belches]
[打嗝]
[groans]
[呻吟]
Now, how can I help you?
现在，我能帮你什么忙？
There's a worm
somewhere outside my house,
有一条虫子
我家外面的某个地方，
and it won't stop barking.
它不会停止吠叫。
I'll get on that right away.
我会立即着手处理。
[animal sounds]
[动物的声音]
I gotta go catch a stray.
我得去抓一只流浪狗。
SpongeBob, you hold down
the fort.
海绵宝宝，你按住
堡垒。
Sir, yes, sir.
先生，是的，先生。
I will take care
of these wild worms
我会照顾的
这些野生蠕虫
to the best of my ability.
尽我所能。
[laughs]
[笑]
[sighs]
[叹气]
[laughing]
[笑]
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
[playful music]
[有趣的音乐]
[gasps]
- Uh-oh.
[喘气]
- 呃哦。
B-B-Butcher's cage.
B-B-屠夫的笼子。
[nervous whimpering]
[紧张的呜咽]
- [barks]
- [screams]
- [吠叫]
- [尖叫]
Butcher?
屠夫？
I know you're really a good boy.
我知道你真的是一个好孩子。
Just let me pet you,
就让我宠你吧
real gentle.
真的很温柔。
That a boy.
那是个男孩。
[growls and snarls]
[咆哮和咆哮]
[gasps]
[喘气]
I hope he doesn't develop
a taste for sponge.
希望他不要发展
海绵的味道。
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
[animal sounds]
[动物的声音]
[straining]
[紧张]
[barking]
[叫声]
Whoa... whoa!
哇...哇！
- [barking]
- Whoa-whoa.
- [吠叫]
- 哇哇。
[barking]
[叫声]
Patrick.
帕特里克.
Yeah, aw... who's a good boy?
是啊，噢……谁是个好孩子？
Who's a good boy?
谁是好孩子？
[panting]
Huh?
[气喘吁吁]
啊？
Patrick's my friend.
帕特里克是我的朋友。
Sometimes if he's eaten
worm food by mistake,
有时候如果他吃饱了
错误地喂食蠕虫，
he's goes into worm mode.
他进入了蠕虫模式。
[growls]
[咆哮]
There's no telling how long
it'll last.
不知道要多久
它会持续下去。
Well, if he's not trained
in a few days
好吧，如果他没有受过训练
几天后
so he can be adopted,
he'll have to be locked up,
这样他就可以被收养
他必须被关起来
like Butcher.
就像屠夫一样。
[growls]
[咆哮]
Don't worry, sir.
别担心，先生。
I'll train him.
He's already housebroken.
我会训练他。
他已经家破人亡了。
[liquid trickling]
[液体滴落]
[nervous laughs]
I knew he was broken.
[紧张的笑声]
我知道他已经崩溃了。
I thought it was house.
我还以为是房子呢
Uh...
呃...
[playful music]
[有趣的音乐]
Now, Patrick,
现在，帕特里克，
every good worm needs to learn
how to do tricks.
每只优秀的蠕虫都需要学习
如何做技巧。
Then they get wormy treats
as a reward.
然后他们会得到蠕虫食物
作为奖励。
Sit.
坐。
[excited barks]
[兴奋的吠叫]
Um... almost.
嗯……差不多了。
Let's try another one.
让我们尝试另一个。
Shake.
摇。
[excited barks]
[兴奋的吠叫]
[pants]
- Shall we try roll over?
[裤子]
- 我们要尝试翻身吗？
[excited barks]
[兴奋的吠叫]
Patrick, wait.
帕特里克，等等。
[crashing]
[崩溃]
[playful music]
[有趣的音乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
Rolling Star Express,
right on time.
滚星快车，
准时。
[pants]
[裤子]
I know one wormy
that needs a bath.
我认识一只虫子
需要洗澡。
[growls]
[咆哮]
Okay, okay, no bath, no bath.
好了好了，不洗澡了，不洗澡了。
Here, Patrick.
在这里，帕特里克。
Worms learn from other worms.
蠕虫向其他蠕虫学习。
They'll show you
how to be a good boy.
他们会告诉你
如何做一个好孩子。
[playful music]
[有趣的音乐]
Hmm?
唔？
[sophisticated barks]
[复杂的吠叫]
[cheers]
[干杯]
[gasps]
[喘气]
[barks]
[吠叫]
Huh?
啊？
This worm is a menace.
这种蠕虫是一种威胁。
I'm afraid he'll have to be
locked up,
恐怕他必须是
被锁起来,
like Butcher.
就像屠夫一样。
Please don't do that.
请不要这样做。
I'll adopt him.
I'll take him home.
我会收养他。
我会带他回家。
He'll be my rescue.
他会是我的拯救者。
And you'll take full
responsibility for him?
而你将充分
对他负责？
- [pants]
- I promise.
- [裤子]
- 我保证。
Well, that's good.
嗯，那很好。
I really didn't want to have
to fix him, anyway.
我真的不想拥有
无论如何，要修复他。
[excited barks]
[兴奋的吠叫]
Thank you, thank you.
谢谢，谢谢。
Patrick, whoa, boy.
帕特里克，哇，男孩。
Heel.
脚跟。
Sorry.
对不起。
Oh, Gary...
哦，加里...
I brought you a playmate.
我给你带来了一个玩伴。
[meows]
[喵喵]
[barks]
[吠叫]
- [screeches]
- [barks]
- [尖叫声]
- [吠叫]
[animal sounds]
[动物的声音]
Patrick, Gary, no, stop.
帕特里克，加里，不，停下来。
[barking]
[叫声]
Hmm?
唔？
[meows]
[喵喵]
[barking]
[叫声]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
[playful music]
[有趣的音乐]
[barking]
[叫声]
[rooster crows]
[公鸡打鸣]
SpongeBob!
海绵宝宝！
[pounds on door]
[敲门]
Come on.
快点。
[groans]
I'm sorry.
[呻吟]
对不起。
Was the noise bothering you?
噪音打扰到您了吗？
[barking]
[叫声]
[energized music]
[充满活力的音乐]
Patrick, heel.
帕特里克，脚后跟。
[yells]
[喊叫]
[barking]
[叫声]
[gasping]
[喘气]
Jeez.
天啊。
[meows]
[喵喵]
Huh. Look.
呵呵。看。
I don't care what kind
of weird and stupid parties
我不在乎什么样的
奇怪而愚蠢的派对
you throw, I'm just asking that
you keep your pet quiet.
你扔，我只是问这个
你让你的宠物保持安静。
I am at my wit's end.
我已经无计可施了。
Patrick is in worm mode again.
帕特里克再次进入蠕虫模式。
But this time,
he's out of control.
但这一次，
他失控了。
Oh, any worm can be tamed.
哦，任何蠕虫都可以被驯服。
Even one as dumb as Patrick.
即使像帕特里克这样愚蠢的人也是如此。
He just needs tough love.
他只是需要严厉的爱。
Would you tough-love Patrick,
Squidward?
你会严厉地爱帕特里克吗？
章鱼哥？
No way.
决不。
[barking]
[叫声]
Please, Squidward.
求你了，章鱼哥。
I bet you're the best
worm trainer ever.
我打赌你是最好的
曾经的蠕虫训练师。
Please.
请。
[laughs]
[笑]
Beg me.
求我吧。
[barks]
[吠叫]
Okay, sit.
好吧，坐吧。
Huh?
啊？
Well, I'm a good idiot trainer.
嗯，我是一个很好的白痴教练。
And since Patrick's an idiot...
既然帕特里克是个白痴......
Okay, I'll train him.
好的，我会训练他。
But only if you play dead...
但前提是你装死...
[gasps]
[喘气]
[laughs]
And stay playing dead.
[笑]
并继续装死。
I've got an idiot to train.
我有一个白痴要训练。
[playful tone]
[俏皮的语气]
[straining]
[紧张]
We'll start with something simple.
我们将从简单的事情开始。
I'll teach you how to heel.
我来教你如何跟好。
Now... be a good boy.
现在...做一个好孩子。
[growls]
[咆哮]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
Heel... stop!
脚后跟……停下来！
Heel.
- [growls]
脚跟。
- [咆哮]
[playful music]
[有趣的音乐]
All right, that's it.
好吧，就是这样。
[energized music]
[充满活力的音乐]
[pants]
[裤子]
Have a nice life.
祝你生活愉快。
[coyote howls]
[土狼嚎叫]
[playful music]
[有趣的音乐]
- [hums]
- Hi, Squidward.
- [哼哼]
- 嗨，章鱼哥。
I'm still playing dead.
[laughs]
我还在装死。
[笑]
[hums]
[哼哼]
Tough love.
[laughs]
艰难的爱。
[笑]
Huh?
[pounding on door]
啊？
[敲门]
[pants]
[裤子]
[winces]
[退缩]
[playful tone]
[俏皮的语气]
This, my little barking friend,
这个，我的小吠叫朋友，
is a shock collar.
是一个防震项圈。
Whenever you bark,
I'll push this button
每当你吠叫时，
我会按下这个按钮
and give you
a mild tough-love shock.
并给你
一种温和的严厉的爱的冲击。
[pants]
[裤子]
Hmm?
唔？
Nothing?
没有什么？
Oh, it must be broken.
哦，一定是坏掉了。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Nuts.
坚果。
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[barks]
[吠叫]
[energized music]
[充满活力的音乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[barks]
[吠叫]
[playful music]
[有趣的音乐]
Still playing dead.
还装死。
[mutters]
[嘀咕]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
- [growls]
- [nervous whimper]
- [咆哮]
- [紧张的呜咽]
[energized music]
[充满活力的音乐]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
- Oh.
- [barks]
- 哦。
- [吠叫]
[pants]
[裤子]
[playful music]
[有趣的音乐]
[pants]
[裤子]
[whimpers]
[呜咽]
[barks]
[吠叫]
Excuse, Mr. Squidward.
对不起，章鱼哥先生。
SpongeBob tells me
that you've trained Patrick
海绵宝宝告诉我
你训练过帕特里克
using tough love.
用严厉的爱。
Patrick? He's impossible.
帕特里克？他是不可能的。
I've tried to get him to sit...
我试着让他坐下...
[barks]
[吠叫]
Hmm...
唔...
Okay, well, then I tried to get
him to beg...
好吧，然后我尝试着
他求...
[pants]
[裤子]
Spin.
旋转。
Now shake.
现在摇一摇。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Cheerleader split.
啦啦队长分裂。
[fanfare]
[大张旗鼓]
- Chicken.
- [chicken sounds]
- 鸡。
- [鸡的声音]
Chicken nugget.
鸡块。
Air guitar.
空气吉他.
[rock music]
[摇滚乐]
[pants]
[裤子]
[laughs]
[笑]
Now play dead.
现在装死。
What? You did it.
什么？你做到了。
You're a miracle worker.
你是一个创造奇迹的人。
Well, I don't like to brag,
but...
嗯，我不喜欢炫耀，
但是...
That's great.
那太棒了。
We've got a problem worm
that needs training.
我们遇到了一个有问题的蠕虫
需要培训。
- What?
- [whistles]
- 什么？
- [口哨]
Bring him in, fellas!
把他带进来吧，伙计们！
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
Say hello to Butcher.
向屠夫问好。
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[animal sounds]
[动物的声音]
Heel, heel!
脚跟，脚跟！
Ah, stop... heel, heel...
fetch, heel, heel!
啊，停下来……脚跟，脚跟……
拿来，脚后跟，脚后跟！
Hey, you're not a worm anymore.
嘿，你不再是一条虫子了。
Nah, I snapped out of it
hours ago.
不，我突然醒悟了
几个小时前。
I just wanted Squidward to feel
like he did a good job.
我只是想让章鱼哥感觉到
就像他做得很好一样。
All right, that's enough.
好吧，够了。
I'll teach you!
- Yeah, I hope Squidward's
我来教你！
- 是的，我希望是章鱼哥的
not too tough on him.
- Will you sit... good dog sit.
对他不太严厉。
- 你愿意坐吗...好狗坐。
Will you sit? No... don't.
你会坐吗？不……不要。
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
下午好，先生们。
Nice day for a walk.
散步的好日子。
[both gasp]
[两人都喘气]